Guide to the Randolph H. Lytton Historical Virginia collection, 1670-2004
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Randolph H. Lytton Historical Virginia collection
1670-2004
C0311
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
15 linear ft. (11 boxes)
This collection includes artwork, correspondence, indentures, maps, newspapers, photographs, postcards, and publications from 1670-2004.
Lytton, Randolph H.
Box 1-11
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by George Mason University Emeritus Faculty member Randolph H. Lytton from 2004 to 2015.
Historical Information
Fairfax County was originally granted to Thomas Fairfax, Sixth Lord Fairfax of Cameron by Charles II in 1719. It was not until 1742 that the Virginia Assembly officially established Fairfax as a county. Throughout the 18th century, Fairfax modernized in the form of industry and trade. With modernization, Fairfax County was fractured into Alexandria, Arlington, Falls Church, and Loudon. It was also during the time period that the Fairfax Courthouse was constructed with the financial aid of Richard Ratcliffe.
The 19th century brought conflict and subsequent growth to Fairfax County. Many Civil War battles took place within the county as well as the first land engagement of the American Civil War, which took place on June 1, 1861. During the war, Fairfax Courthouse changed hands many times between the Union and Confederacy. After the war, Fairfax experienced economic growth but also remained an agrarian-driven area. By the mid-20th century, Fairfax had experienced a massive population boom, largely as a result of President Roosevelt's increase in government programs, which produced large numbers of new citizens within Fairfax itself. The growth within Fairfax continues today.
Scope and Content
The collection includes artwork, campaign materials, correspondence, envelopes, indentures, maps, military paperwork, newspapers, paper currency, photographs, postcards, and publications. The items in the collection were collected by George Mason University Emeritus Faculty member Randolph H. Lytton. The collection is arranged into five series:
Series 1: Postcards (1903-1982) includes postcards from Virginia.
Series 2: Civil War Era Materials (1861-1914) includes artwork, letters, maps, military paperwork, newspapers, paper currency, and photographs.
Series 3: George Washington (circa 1700-1960) includes artwork, envelopes, maps, photographs and postcards.
Series 4: Fairfax Family (1670-1975) includes artwork, correspondence, indentures, photographs, postcards, and stamps.
Series 5: Mixed Media (1712-2004) includes advertisements, campaign materials, maps, money orders, photographs, and publications.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Series 1: Postcards, 1903-1982 (Boxes 1-2)
Series 2: Civil War Era Materials, 1861-1914 (Boxes 2-5)
Series 3: George Washington, circa 1700-1960 (Box 5)
Series 4: Fairfax Family, 1670-1975 (Box 6)
Series 5: Mixed Media, 1712-2004 (Boxes 7-11)
Bibliography
Index Terms
Persons:
Lytton, Randolph H.
Subjects:
Letters.; Maps.; Photography.; Presidents--United States.; Slides.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Virginia--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Maps.; Virginia, Northern--History, Local.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Maps.; Newspapers.; Photographs.; Photographic prints.; Reproductions.; Slides.; Tintypes.
Contents List
- Series 1: Postcards, 1903-1982 (Boxes 1-2)
  This series includes postcards from Virginia.
  - Fairfax, VA (1 of 2), 1907-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax, VA (2 of 2), 1907-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accotink, VA, 1908-1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alexandria, VA, 1903-1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arlington, VA, 1909-1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Manassas, VA, 1911-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Centreville, VA, 1904-1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chantilly, VA, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dranesville, VA, 1909-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annandale, VA, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clifton, VA, 1906-1913 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Falls Church, VA, 1907-1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lorton, VA-Gunston Hall, circa 1910s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Covington, VA, 1948-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Great Falls, VA, 1905-1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Occoquan, VA, 1907-1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vienna, VA, 1905-1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Reston, VA, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Warrenton, VA, 1909-1931 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Herndon, VA, 1909-1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - McLean, VA, 1915-1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Oakton, VA, 1909-1914 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Civil War Materials, 1861-1914 (Boxes 2-5)
  This series includes artwork, letters, maps, military paperwork, newspapers, paper currency, and photographs related to the American Civil War.
  - Matthew Brady salt print of Culpepper Courthouse, circa 1860s (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Autograph book, 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photogravures of Union Officers Philip Kearny and Franz Sigel, circa 1860s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 2.5x4 inch photographs of soldiers in uniform, circa 1860s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 3.5x5 inch photographs of soldiers in uniform, circa 1860s (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Harper's Magazine, July 1861; June 1876 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "3rd Battalion Sharpshooters" by W.R. Montgomery, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Vanity Fair, June 22, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Soldier's Textbook" by J.R. Macduff, circa 1870 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Illustrations of battles, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of soldiers stationed at Camp Algier, circa 1890s (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Glass slides of Civil War battlefields, circa 1860s (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Historic newspapers (1 of 2), 1861-1865 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Historic newspapers (2 of 2), 1861-1865 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Historic newspaper illustrations, 1861-1868 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Photographs of John Mosby and Mosby's Raiders, circa 1860s (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Sheet music for Colonel Ellsworth's funeral march, 1861 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Drawings of Fairfax Courthouse and Cider Press by Eugene B. Hovey, June 18, 1862; June 5, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs and illustrations of Fairfax Courthouse, 1863;1925-2012 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax Courthouse Documents, November 1744-May 1888 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Tax bills and receipts, 1740; 1845-1874 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Letter about property costs-Thomas R. Love, Thomas B. Smith, November 21, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Recorded agreement-Seth M. Perkins, S. Childs, October 2, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Confederate Veteran", September 1, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 76th Pennsylvania Infantry Bill of Fare parody, circa 1862 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Aronon Chapel account book, 1909-1914 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Biographical sketches of Allan, Emma, and Myron Williams, circa 1910s (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Letter-soldier stationed at Camp Alger, July 2, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Letter-Samuel Hand, December 3, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letter-S.H. Reynolds, June 13, 1859 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Letter-Emily Hunter, Fairfax Company, July 10, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Letter-H. August, mentions Bull Run, July 28, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Letter-Franklin L. Stuart, Fairfax Station, October 11, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Letter-soldier stationed at Camp Pierpoint, October 12, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Letter-John F. Putney, Fairfax, Virginia, December 17, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Letter-Charles Skinner, New York 26th Regiment, October 26, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Letter-F.F. Burmeister, Fairfax Courthouse, October 4, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Letter-Charles A. Newman, Fairfax Courthouse, October 10, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Letter-James Alfred Mead, October 15, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Letter-soldier stationed at Fairfax Courthouse, October 14, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Letter with envelope-George W. Newcomb, Fairfax Courthouse, written on "The Soldier's Address", October 24, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Letter with envelope-Samuel Willard, Fairfax Courthouse, October 30, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Letter-11th corps written to E.D. Morgan, Fairfax Courthouse, December 8, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Letter with envelope-Fairfax Courthouse, written in German, December 8, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Letter with envelope-Fairfax Courthouse, written in German, October 14, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Letter with envelope-Fairfax Courthouse, written in German, January 12, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Letter-Union soldier, Union Mills, Virginia, December 14, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Letter-Union soldier, Alexandria, Virginia, December 31, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Letter-Union soldier, camp near Fairfax Courthouse, January 6, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Letter with envelope-Union Soldier, camp near Fairfax Courthouse, January 8, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Letter-Union soldier, Fairfax Courthouse, January 12, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Letter with envelope-P.B. Chamberlin, Camp Fairfax, January 13, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Letter-Union soldier, camp near Fairfax Courthouse, January 18, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Letter-Union soldier, Chantilly, Virginia, March 31, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Letter-Union soldier, camp near Fairfax Courthouse, April 18, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Letter-W. Barnett, Union Mills, Virginia, May 2, 1868 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Letter-Union soldier, Fairfax Station, June 17, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Letter-S.W. Bosworth, camp near Fairfax Station, June 19, 1868 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Letters-Timothy S. Walker, Arlington Heights, Virginia, March 23, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Letters with envelopes-Timothy S. Walker, Chantilly, Virginia, April 7-May 31, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Letter with envelope-Giles Weeks, Fairfax, Virginia, May 16, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Letter with envelope-Lair Mason, Chantilly, Virginia, April 11, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Letter-Bernard Ferry, Fairfax, Virginia, June 3, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Letter-Union soldier, camp near Fairfax, Virginia, June 21, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Letter-Union soldier, Upton Hill, Virginia, April 27, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Letter-Frank Ripley, Chantilly, Virginia, October 17, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Letters-Henry E. Alvord, Washington, D.C., June 28, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Letter-Burkes' Station, November 12, 1864 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Letter with envelope-Horatio Eggleston, Alexandria, Virginia, December 1, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Letter-Union soldier, Camp McNulty, September 18, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Letter with envelope-Henry B. Crosby, camp near Centreville, Virginia, October 25, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Letter with envelope-J. Stall, Pleasant Valley, February 6, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Letter-Confederate soldier, camp at Manassas Junction, Virginia, May 29, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Letter-Union soldier, camp near Fairfax Courthouse, December 28, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Letter-Ellis C. Strouss, Fairfax Station, October 16, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Letter-Cyrus Adset, Fairfax, Virginia, February 16, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Letter-soldier stationed at Fairfax Courthouse, March 13, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Letter-soldier stationed in Alexandria, Virginia, circa 1864 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Letter-S. Howard, Fairfax Station, April 29, 1864 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Letter-Washington, D.C., December 9, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Letters-M. Victoria Wailes, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Envelopes-Northern Virginia, 1861-1961 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Envelopes-Civil War propaganda, 1860s (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Envelopes-Soldiers stationed in Fairfax, Virginia, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Account book and memorandum-John DeBell, June 1, 1849 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Battlefield maps, 1862-1864 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Orders from General Milledge Luke Bonham, July 5, 1864 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Passes for Union soldiers, July 11, 1861-April 18, 1863 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pass for Confederate soldier M. Pierce Butler, July 18, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fuel requisition form-Fairfax, Virginia, November 25, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Paper currency-Joshua C. Gunnell, Fairfax Courthouse, September 20, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Reports, May 1862; March 1870 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Military paperwork and orders, October 1863-June 1865 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Special Order No. 7, Centreville, Virginia, September 5, 1863 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Union Battle Hymn, 1863 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Democratic election materials, 1864; 1892 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Series 3: George Washington, circa 1700-1960 (Box 5)
  This series includes artwork, envelopes, maps, photographs and postcards all related to George Washington
  - Prints and glass slides of George Washington, circa 1780 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Print of Admiral Vernon, circa 1700 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Civil War tin type of former slaves, circa 1860s (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Framed silhouette of George Washington, circa 1900 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Silhouettes of George and Martha Washington, circa 1900 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - George Washington birthday programs, 1862; 1903 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - George Washington Bicentennial stamp covers and pamphlets, 1932-1960 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Authenticated copy of Last Will and Testament of George Washington, 1868 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Civil War era envelopes, circa 1860s (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "The Story of Young Surveyors" by W.H. Snowden, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 2-)
  - Two stereo optics of Mount Vernon and the Tomb of George Washington, circa 1872 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Century Magazine Volume 35, November 1887 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Mount Vernon postcards, 1906-1948 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Robert Nesbit sketch of George Washington, 1932 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Map of the principal events in the life of George Washington, 1932 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
- Series 4: Fairfax Family, 1670-1975 (Box 6)
  This series includes artwork, correspondence, indentures photographs, postcards, and stamps all related to the Fairfax family.
  - Portraits of Thomas Fairfax (1 of 2), circa 18th century (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Portraits of Thomas Fairfax (2 of 2), circa 18th century (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Postcards from Leeds Castle and Greenway Court, 1905-1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of the Belvoir Estate, circa 1890s (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Proceedings of the Clarke County Historical Association, Volume VIII", 1948 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Christmas card from the British War Office, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Civil War 350th anniversary stamp cover, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Lord Fairfax Boy Scout patch, circa 1950s (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Winchester, VA Bicentennial envelope, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "My Lord Fairfax, Of Virginia", circa 1800s (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letter-John Hunter, George William Fairfax, April 10, 1753 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Indenture-Thomas Fairfax, John Peyton, 1790 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Survey documents-Henry Fairfax, October 12, 1829 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Graphic of Thomas Fairfax kissing the King's hand, circa 19th century (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Signed Biddenden County Parish removal notice, December 6, 1742 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Graphic of George Washington dancing with Sally Fairfax, circa 1760s (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Portraits of Ferdinand Lord Fairfax, 1800 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letters-H. Fairfax, 1799-1800 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Henry Fairfax, September 25, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pamphlet on Sir Thomas Fairfax, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Letter-Ann Clinton, Mary Fairfax, July 18, 1692 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Tax notice-Bryan Fairfax, 8th Lord of Cameron, 1754 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Drawing of the heraldry of Thomas Lord Culpepper, circa 18th century (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Engraving of Leeds Castle, Kent, September 10, 1784 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Letter-Sale agreement, Charles Martin, October 10, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Letter-John Marshall, Manor of Leeds, February 17, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Indentures concerning land and property, 1814-1837 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Tax Notices- Bryan Fairfax, 1721 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Land deeds, 1759 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Facsimile letters-Thomas Fairfax and Oliver Cromwell, circa 1950s (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Map of Yorkshire-Richard Blome, 1670 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Land deeds, 1759-1900 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Letter about land-N. Elliot, June 18, 1802 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Will of Sarah Fairfax, 1811 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Indentures-Robert Fairfax, 1685; 1720 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Indenture-Richard Fairfax, 1797 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
- Series 5: Mixed Media, 1712-2004 (Boxes 7-11)
  This series includes advertisements, campaign materials, maps, money orders, photographs, and publications.
  - Photograph of Constance Cary Harrison with autograph, circa 1900 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of the Moore House in Fairfax, VA, circa 1900s (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Kate Waller Barrett, circa 1900 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Wire story photographs, 1954-1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - House of Commons proceedings, 1809 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Fairfax, VA, 1910; 1942-1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Herndon, VA (1 of 2), 1905 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Herndon, VA (2 of 2), 1928-1960 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 3.5x5 inch photographs of the Indiana Railroad, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of memorials in Virginia, circa 1920s (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Tribune photographs, 1916-1933 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Fold-out maps of Virginia (1 of 2), 1939-1998 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Fold-out maps of Virginia (2 of 2), 1939-1998 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Photograph of R.E. Lee Klan convention-Roanoke, VA, May 30, 1931 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Two John Jackson LP vinyl records, 1966; 1968 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Maps of Virginia (1 of 2), 1879-1990 (Box Map case, Folder 13.5)
  - Maps of Virginia (2 of 2), 1912-1989 (Box Map case, Folder 13.5)
  - Fairfax Tourism Materials (1 of 4), 1983-2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax Tourism Materials (2 of 4), 1992-2000 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax Tourism Materials (3 of 4), 1992-2004 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax Tourism Materials (4 of 4), 1992-2004 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Technician certification awards, 1933-1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Publications about home gardening, 1909-1910 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Matchbook covers for Fairfax businesses (1 of 2), circa 20th century (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Matchbook covers for Fairfax businesses (2 of 2), circa 20th century (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Advertisements for businesses in Fairfax, VA, 1907-1957 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Letter to Weel Radio Station, November 1, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letters and envelopes-Joseph E. Willard (1 of 2), 1895-1933 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Letters and envelopes-Joseph E. Willard (2 of 2), 1895-1933 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Northern Virginia postal money orders, 1906-1910 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - First day stamp covers, 1934-1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Letters and envelopes related to Fairfax, VA, 1820-1939 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Contracts for businesses in Fairfax, VA, 1899-1961 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Letter-Lucy Post Frisbee, Claudia Johnson, December 9, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Postcards and photographs from Fort Belvoir, 1925-1942 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Runaway slave advertisement, February 14, 1823 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The London Gazette, March 1713; August 1755 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Spectator, March and November 1712 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - New York Weekly Museum, March 17, 1810 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Pathfinder: Digest of the World, October 1933; August 1936 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - The Tatler, November 12, 1709 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Materials, 1904-1934 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Fairfax County democratic rally materials, 1928; 1944 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Northern Virginia Transportation Co. materials, 1915-1962 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Fairfax public school materials, 1951-1955 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Spanish-American War ribbons, circa 1900 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - U.S.S Fairfax County LST-1193 photographs and news clippings, circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Publications mentioning Fairfax, VA, 1917; 1929 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Indian arrow heads from Fairfax, VA, circa pre-18th century (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Various items related to Fairfax, VA, 1941-1960 (Box Map case, Folder 13.4)
  - Film reel-"The Boyhood of George Washington", circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)